Thomas Szasz Papers
Thomas Szasz Papers
- Writings by Szasz
  - Books
    - Hinckley, 1982; manuscript proposal draft (Box 215)
    - Ideology and Insanity
      - Drafts
        - Draft A, 3 folders (Box 215)
        - Draft B, 2 folders (Box 215)
        - Draft B, 1 folder (Box 216)
        - Draft C, 3 folders (Box 216)
      - Chapter drafts
        - Preface, includes original 1970 and updated 1991 edition (Box 216)
        - Introduction, 2 folders (Box 216)
        - Chapters 2-3, includes photocopies of chapter 2 from book (Box 217)
        - Chapter 4 (Box 217)
        - Chapters 5-8 (Box 217)
        - Chapter 9, includes 2 photocopies of chapter from book (Box 217)
        - Chapter 10-11 (Box 217)
        - Chapter 12-13 (Box 217)
        - Cover text (Box 217)
      - Galleys
        - Galley A (Box 311)
        - Galley B (Box 311)
        - Galley C (Box 311)
        - Galley D (Box 312)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 217)
      - Reviews (Box 217)
    - In the Name of Help. The American Psychiatric Tragedy, appears to be a beginning to a book that was never published
      - Draft TOC, Preface, and Introduction, various copies (Box 218)
    - Insanity: The Idea and Its Consequences, several drafts have working title "The Idea of Insanity"
      - Drafts
        - Draft A, 4 folders (Box 218)
        - Draft B, pp. 2-157, 1 folder (Box 218)
        - Draft B, pp. 158-655, 3 folders (Box 219)
        - Draft C, pp. 1-470, 3 folders (Box 219)
        - Draft C, pp. 471-672, 1 folder (Box 220)
        - Draft D, "9/20/85 revisions" (Box 220)
        - Draft E, includes addendum from 7/1/85; 2 folders (Box 220)
        - Draft F, 2 folders (Box 220)
        - Draft G, 2 folders (Box 221)
        - Draft H, 2 folders (Box 221)
        - Draft I, pp. 1-192, incomplete (Box 221)
        - Draft J, pp. 1-399, 2 folders (Box 221)
        - Draft J, pp. 400-614, 1 folder (Box 222)
      - Chapter drafts
        - Table of Contents (Box 222)
        - Preface (Box 222)
        - Introduction (Box 222)
        - Chapter 1 (Defining Illness), 2 folders (Box 222)
        - Chapter 2 (Being a Patient) (Box 222)
        - Chapter 3 (Defining Mental Illness), 6 folders (Box 223)
        - Chapter 4 (Being a Mental Patient), 1 folder (Box 223)
        - Chapter 4 (Being a Mental Patient), 3 folders (Box 224)
        - Chapter 5 (Mental Illness as Metaphor), 3 folders (Box 224)
        - Chapter 6 (Mental Illness and the Problem of Imitation), 1 folder (Box 224)
        - Chapter 6 (Mental Illness and the Problem of Imitation), 2 folders (Box 225)
        - Chapter 7 (Mental Illness and the Problem of Intentionality), 2 folders (Box 225)
        - Chapter 8 (Mental Illness and the problem of Responsibility), 3 folders (Box 225)
        - Chapter 8 (Mental Illness and the problem of Responsibility), 1 folder (Box 226)
        - Chapter 9 (Mental Illness as Strategy), 2 folders (Box 226)
        - Chapter 10 (Mental Illness as Justification) (Box 226)
        - Chapter 11 (Mental Illness as Legal Fiction), 3 folders (Box 226)
        - Chapter 12 (Mental Illness as Explanation), 2 folders (Box 227)
        - Epilogue, published book has no Epilogue (Box 227)
        - References, 3 folders (Box 227)
        - Indexes (Box 227)
      - Drafts, unidentified
        - Miscellaneous fragments, 1 folder (Box 227)
        - Miscellaneous fragments, 2 folders (Box 228)
        - Miscellaneous (Box 228)
      - Proofs, 6 folders
        - Proof A (Box 312)
        - Proof B (Box 312)
        - Proof C (Box 312)
        - Proof D (Box 312)
        - Proof E (Box 313)
        - Proof F (partial) (Box 313)
      - Research materials, includes correspondence; 4 folders (Box 228)
      - Promotional materials (Box 228)
      - Reviews, includes correspondence (Box 228)
    - Karl Kraus and the Soul-Doctors: A Pioneer Critic and His Criticism of Psychiatry and Psychoanalysis
      - Correspondence, 1975-1978; with publishers and personal (Box 228)
      - Drafts
        - Draft A, 2 folders (Box 229)
        - Draft B, 2 folders (Box 229)
        - Draft C, 2 folders (Box 229)
        - Draft D, 1 folder (Box 229)
        - Draft D, 1 folder (Box 230)
        - Draft E, 3 folders (Box 230)
      - Draft, alternate title (original title?) "The Urn and the Chamber Pot" or "The Urn and the Urinal"; appears to be chapters 6-8 of the published book, which deal with Kraus's own writings (Box 230)
      - Chapter drafts
        - Preface (Box 230)
        - Preface to the French edition [1986] (Box 230)
        - Preface to the German edition (Box 230)
        - Preface for the Syracuse University Press edition [1990], 1 folder (Box 230)
        - Preface for the Syracuse University Press edition [1990], 1 folder (Box 231)
        - Chapter 1 (The Man and His Work) (Box 231)
        - Chapter 2 (Kraus and Freud: Unmasking the Unmasker), 2 folders (Box 231)
        - Chapter 3 (Karl Kraus: Noble Rhetorician) (Box 231)
        - Chapter 4 (Kraus's Place in Cultural History) (Box 231)
        - Chapter 5 (Karl Kraus Today) (Box 231)
        - Chapter 6 (On Psychoanalysis and Psychology) (Box 231)
        - Chapter 7 (On Institutional and Forensic Psychology) (Box 232)
        - Chapter 8 (On Language, Life, and Love) (Box 232)
        - Summary (Box 232)
        - Miscellaneous drafts and fragments, 2 folders (Box 232)
      - Draft setting copies
        - Typescript, 3 folders (Box 232)
        - "New Copy Set" (Box 232)
        - "Printer's Set, Revised Pages" (Box 233)
      - Galleys, 3 folders (Box 233)
      - Promotional Materials (Box 233)
      - Proofs, photocopies; 3 folders (Box 233)
      - References (Box 234)
      - Research Materials (Box 234)
      - Reviews (Box 234)
    - Language and Lunacy, unpublished book of previous written columns, essays, letters, and discussions; other titles suggested include "Why Nixon Hates Psychiatrists"; "Freedom and Folly"; "Freedom: the American Disease"
      - Table of contents and suggested titles (Box 234)
    - Law, Liberty and Psychiatry: An Inquiry into the Social Uses of Mental Health Practices
      - Drafts
        - "Preface to the Italian edition" (Box 234)
        - "Preface to the Routledge edition", 2 folders (Box 234)
        - "Preface for the Syracuse University Press edition", photocopied proofs; 2 folders (Box 234)
        - Preface fragments, unknown edition (Box 234)
      - Promotional (Box 234)
      - Reviews, 3 folders (Box 234)
      - Reviews, 2 folders (Box 235)
    - A Lexicon of Lunacy: Metaphoric Malady, Moral Responsibility and Psychiatry
      - Drafts
        - Draft A (Box 235)
        - Draft B, 3 folders (Box 235)
        - Draft C, "Unedited and Unproofed Copy", 2 folders (Box 235)
      - Chapter drafts, 2 folders (Box 236)
      - Proof, 2 folders (Box 236)
      - Reviews (Box 236)
    - Liberation by Oppression: a Comparative Study of Slavery and Psychiatry
      - Drafts
        - Draft A, 3 folders (Box 236)
        - Draft B, pp. 1-125, 1 folder (Box 236)
        - Draft B, pp. 126-351, 2 folders (Box 237)
        - Draft C, 3 folders (Box 237)
        - Draft D, 3 folders (Box 237)
        - Draft E, 3 folders (Box 238)
      - Proofs
        - Proof A, 2 folders (Box 238)
        - Proof B, 2 folders (Box 238)
        - Proof C, 2 folders (Box 239)
        - Proof D, "1/16/02", annotated as "[corrected] ½7/02"; 2 folders (Box 239)
      - Unbound Signatures (Box 239)
      - Reviews (Box 239)
    - The Manufacture of Madness: A Comparative Study of the Inquisition and the Mental Health Movement
      - Correspondence, with publisher, includes reviewer comments (Box 239)
      - Brief description [of book]
      - Draft A
        - Chapter 1 "The Threat Defined: Criteria of Witchcraft and Mental Illness" "1/19/68", marked as "chapter 2" (Box 239)
        - Chapter 2 "The Malefactor Identified: Witch Finding and Psychodiagnosis" "½8", marked as "chapter 3" (Box 239)
        - Chapter 3 "The Malefactor Authenticated: The Witch Trial and the Sanity Hearing" "½1/68", marked as "chapter 4" (Box 239)
        - Chapter 4 "The Social Function of the Inquisition and of Institutional Psychiatry: The Defense of the Dominant Ethic" "1/6/68", marked as "chapter 5" (Box 239)
        - Chapter 5 "2/24/68", the other "2/26/68", marked as "chapter 6", 2 copies (Box 240)
        - Chapter 6 "2/7/68?", marked as "chapter 7" (Box 240)
        - Chapter 7 marked as "chapter 8" (Box 240)
        - Chapter 8 "2/2", marked as "chapter 9" (Box 240)
        - Chapter 10 "2/21/68", marked as "chapter 11" (Box 240)
        - Chapter 11 "2/2", marked as "chapter 12" (Box 240)
        - Chapter 12 "Psychodiagnosis: the Manufacture of Medical Stigma" "2/2" marked as "chapter 13" (Box 240)
        - Chapter 13 "1/4/68" marked as "chapter 14" (Box 240)
        - Chapter 14 "The Expulsion of Evil: the Ritual Sacrifice of the Scapegoat" "3/2/68" marked as "chapter 15" (Box 240)
        - Chapter 15 "The Struggle for Self-Esteem: Symbolic Cannibalism and the Invalidation of the Other" "3/2/68" marked as "chapter 16" (Box 240)
        - Epilogue, Appendix, "1/8/68" (Box 240)
      - Draft B
        - Contents, Preface, Introduction (Box 241)
        - Chapter 1 "The Threat Defined: Criteria of Witchcraft and Mental Illness" ["5/17" and "6/28/68", both marked as "chapter 2" and "Society"s Internal Enemies and Protectors: Witch and Inquisitor, Madman and Alienist" ["5/23/68", 3 copies in 2 folders (Box 241)
        - Chapter 2 "The Malefactor Identified: Witch Finding and Psychodiagnosis" "5/26", marked as "chapter 3" (Box 241)
        - Chapter 3 "The Malefactor Authenticated: the Witch Trial and the Sanity Hearing" "5/26/68", marked as "chapter 4" (Box 241)
        - Chapter 4 "The Defense of the Dominant Ethic: the Social Function of the Inquisition and of Institutional Psychiatry" "5/26/68", marked as "chapter 5" (Box 241)
        - Chapter 5 "5/26", marked as "chapter 6" (Box 241)
        - Chapter 6 "5/29", marked as "chapter 7" (Box 241)
        - Chapter 7 "5/27/68", marked as "chapter 8" (Box 241)
        - Chapter 8 "6/2/68", marked as "chapter 9" (Box 241)
        - Chapter 9 "6/5/68", marked as "chapter 10" (Box 241)
        - Chapter 10 "7/6/68", marked as "chapter 11" (Box 241)
        - Chapter 11 "6/8/68", marked as "chapter 12" (Box 242)
        - Chapter 12 "Psychodiagnosis: the Manufacture of Medical Stigma" "6/9/68", marked as "chapter 13" (Box 242)
        - Chapter 13 "6/8/68", marked as "chapter 14" (Box 242)
        - Chapter 14 "The Expulsion of Evil: the Ritual Sacrifice of the Scapegoat" "6/8/68", marked as "chapter 15" (Box 242)
        - Chapter 15 "The Struggle for Self-Esteem: Symbolic Cannibalism and the Invalidation of the Other" "6/8/68" (Box 242)
        - Appendix "7/14/68" (Box 242)
      - Drafts C-J
        - Draft C, "preliminary draft 8/8/67", 3 folders (Box 242)
        - Draft D, 7 folders (Box 243)
        - Draft E, 6 folders (Box 244)
        - Draft F, pp. 1-965, [ pp. 1-965]; 6 folders (Box 245)
        - Draft F, pp. 966-1050, [ pp. 966-1050]; 1 folder (Box 246)
        - Draft G, with reviewer's notes; 2 folders (Box 246)
        - Draft H, pp. 1-331, incomplete; 3 folders (Box 246)
        - Draft I, pp. 7-125, 1 folder (Box 246)
        - Draft I, pp. 126-331, 2 folders (Box 247)
        - Draft J, chapter 8-15, marked with initials "HR"; 3 folders (Box 247)
      - Chapter drafts, includes multiple copies, some with corrections and reviewer's notes
        - Contents (Box 247)
        - Preface (Box 247)
        - Introduction (Box 247)
        - Chapter 1 (Society's Internal Enemies and Protectors), working titles "The Threat Defined: Criteria of Witchcraft and Mental Illness" and "Society's Internal Enemies and Protectors: Witch and Inquisitor, Madman and Alienist"; marked as "chapter 2" (Box 247)
        - Chapter 2 (The Malefactor Identified), working titles "The Threat Defined: Criteria of Witchcraft and Mental Illness" (a combination of ch. 2 and 3); "The Inquisition and Institutional Psychiatry" (mostly writings from ch. 2); and "The Malefactor Identified: Witch Finding and Psychodiagnosis"; marked as "chapter 3"; 1 folder (Box 247)
        - Chapter 2 (The Malefactor Identified), working titles "The Threat Defined: Criteria of Witchcraft and Mental Illness" (a combination of ch.2 and 3); "The Inquisition and Institutional Psychiatry" (mostly writings from ch. 2); and "The Malefactor Identified: Witch Finding and Psychodiagnosis"; marked as "chapter 3"; 1 folder (Box 248)
        - Chapter 3 (The Malefactor Authenticated), working title "The Malefactor Authenticated: The Witch Trial and the Sanity Hearing;" marked as "chapter 4" (Box 248)
        - Chapter 4 (The Defense of the Dominant Ethic), working title "The Social Function of the Inquisition and of Institutional Psychiatry: the Defense of the Dominant Ethic"; one copy marked as "chapter 7" and the other as "chapter 5" (Box 248)
        - Chapter 5 (The Witch as Mental Patient), includes elements of both ch. 5 and ch. 12; working title "The New Product: The Mentally Ill as Scapegoat"; marked as "chapter 2" (Box 248)
        - Chapter 6 (The Witch as Healer), marked as "chapter 7" (Box 248)
        - Chapter 7 (The Witch as Scapegoat), marked as "chapter 8" (Box 248)
        - Chapter 8 (The Myths of Witchcraft and Mental Illness), one copy marked as "chapter 7", the other as "chapter 9" (Box 248)
        - Chapter 9 (The New Manufacturer -- Benjamin Rush, the Father of American Psychiatry), some marked as "chapter 10" (Box 248)
        - Chapter 10 (The Product Conversion: From Heresy to Illness), marked as "chapter 11" (Box 248)
        - Chapter 11 (The New Product: Masturbatory Insanity), marked as "chapter 12" (Box 248)
        - Chapter 12 (The Manufacture of Medical Stigma), working title "Psychodiagnosis: the Manufacture of Medical Stigma"; marked as "chapter 13" (Box 249)
        - Chapter 13 (The Model Psychiatric Scapegoat - the Homosexual), marked as "chapter 14" (Box 249)
        - Chapter 14 (The Expulsion of Evil), working title "The Expulsion of Evil: the Ritual Sacrifice of the Scapegoat"; marked as "chapter 15" (Box 249)
        - Chapter 15 (The Struggle for Self-Esteem), working title "The Struggle for Self-Esteem: Symbolic Cannibalism and the Invalidation of the Other"; marked as "chapter 16" (Box 249)
        - Epilogue (Box 249)
        - Bibliography (Box 249)
        - Bibliography (Box 313)
        - Index (Box 249)
        - Addendum to index (Box 249)
      - Draft setting copy
        - Introduction, 1 folder (Box 249)
        - Chapter 1-11, 6 folders (Box 250)
        - Chapter 12 through bibliography, 4 folders (Box 251)
      - Editorial comments and suggested corrections (Box 313)
      - Miscellaneous drafts and corrections, 2 folders (Box 251)
      - Galleys
        - Galley A (Box 313)
        - Galley B (Box 313)
        - Galley C (Box 313)
        - Galley D (Box 313)
        - Galley E (Box 314)
        - Galley F (Box 314)
        - Galley G (Box 314)
        - Galley H (Box 314)
      - Research materials, 1 folder (Box 251)
      - Research materials, 2 folders (Box 252)
      - Promotional materials (Box 252)
      - Reviews, 2 folders (Box 252)
    - The Meaning of Mind: Language, Morality, and Neuroscience, alternate titles appearing in drafts include "Mind: Your Own Business," "The Silent Speech of the Self. The Dialogue Within," and "Mind: Your Own Business. Moral Philosophy in a New Key"
      - Drafts
        - Draft A, 2 folders (Box 252)
        - Draft B, beginning-chapter 3, 1 folder (Box 252)
        - Draft B, chapter 4-end, 1 folder (Box 253)
        - Draft C (Box 253)
        - Draft D (partial) (Box 253)
        - Draft E, 2 folders (Box 253)
        - Draft F (Box 253)
        - Draft G, beginning-chapter 3, 1 folder (Box 253)
        - Draft G, chapter 4-end, 1 folder (Box 254)
        - Draft H, "Mind" "10/95" (Box 254)
        - Draft I, 2 folders (Box 254)
      - Proofs
        - Proof A, "Master corrections 6/96" (Box 254)
        - Proof B, "Master corrections 6/96", photocopy (Box 254)
        - Proof C, with typesetting marks (Box 255)
        - Proof D (Box 255)
        - Proof E, "final 7/15/96" (Box 255)
      - Reviews (Box 255)
    - Medicalization of everyday life: selected essays
      - Drafts
        - Draft A, "Orig. 4/25/06", pp. 1-400, with notes and corrections; 3 folders (Box 255)
        - Draft A, "Orig. 4/25/06", pp. 284-384, with notes and corrections; 1 folder (Box 256)
        - Draft B, "9/06", 2 folders (Box 256)
        - Draft C, "4/19/07" "redline-strikeout copy", includes correspondence; 2 folders (Box 256)
        - Proof, "7/10/2007", includes publisher correspondence; 2 folders (Box 256)
    - The Moral Physician or Illness and Indignity: The Coming Crisis in Medical Ethics, appears to be unpublished; no other material found with this besides the TOC sheet
      - Table of contents (Box 257)
    - My madness saved me: the madness and marriage of Virginia Woolf.
      - Early drafts, unclear if these are an early draft of the later published book or a long essay, as material is similar
        - Draft A, working title "That Snowfield of the Mind, Where man has not Trodden" "Virginia Woolf and Psychoanalysis" (Box 257)
        - Draft B, "3/25/84", working title "A Snow Field Where Even the Print of Birds' Feet is Unknown": Virginia Woolf and Psychoanalysis. (Box 257)
      - Drafts
        - Draft A, possibly incomplete (Box 257)
        - Draft B, possibly incomplete (Box 257)
        - Draft C, working titles "I am Going Mad," "Creating a Scene," and "The Fame Belongs to Me" (Box 257)
        - Draft D, 2 folders (Box 257)
        - Miscellaneous drafts (Box 257)
      - Proof, includes editor comments (Box 258)
      - Research materials, 2 folders (Box 258)
    - The Myth of Mental Illness: Foundations of a Theory of Personal Conduct, drafts appear to be from the Revised Edition, 1974 unless otherwise explicitly stated
      - Drafts
        - Draft A, "Revised June 1971", 3 folders (Box 258)
        - Draft B, preface-ch. 6, 1 folder (Box 258)
        - Draft B, ch. 7-11, 1 folder (Box 259)
        - Draft C, "Revised January 1972", 3 folders (Box 259)
        - Draft D, "Corrected copy…9/28/73", pp. 1-300, includes publisher and editor correspondence; 2 folders (Box 259)
        - Draft D, "Corrected copy…9/28/73", pp. 301-440, includes publisher and editor correspondence; 1 folder (Box 260)
        - Draft E, 4 folders (Box 260)
        - Draft, Setting copy, pp. 1-130, 1 folder (Box 260)
        - Draft, Setting copy, pp. 131-391, 2 folders (Box 261)
        - Book description (Box 261)
        - Index (Box 261)
        - Preface to the French edition (Box 261)
        - Preface to the German edition, includes summary (Box 261)
        - Preface to the Hebrew edition (Box 261)
        - Preface to the Japanese edition (Box 261)
        - Preface to the Paladin edition [UK], includes summary (Box 261)
        - Synopsis, appears to be to the 1961 edition (Box 261)
        - Miscellaneous draft pages, 2 folders (Box 261)
      - Galleys
        - Galley A, 1961 edition (Box 314)
        - Galley B, 1961 edition (Box 315)
        - Galley C, 1961 edition (Box 315)
        - Galley D, "Jan 30 1974" (Box 315)
        - Galley E, "Apr 2 1974" (Box 315)
        - Galley F, "#2" (Box 316)
        - Galley G, "#3" (Box 316)
      - Marked-up copies, published copies marked with changes
        - Dell (Delta) 1961 edition, 2 copies; 2 folders (Box 262)
        - Dell (Delta) 1961 edition, photocopies; 4 folders (Box 262)
        - Paladin edition (Box 262)
      - Promotional materials (Box 262)
      - Reviews
        - in English, includes reviews of 1961 original edition, paperback edition released later, revised edition, and Paladin edition; 1 folder (Box 262)
        - in English, includes reviews of 1961 original edition, paperback edition released later, revised edition, and Paladin edition; 1 folder (Box 263)
        - in French (Box 263)
        - in German (Box 263)
        - in Hungarian (Box 263)
        - in Italian (Box 263)
    - The Myth of Psychotherapy
      - Correspondence, regarding use of book cover photo, includes book description as well (Box 263)
      - Drafts (Box 263)
        - Critique Statement, Definition, and Qualification Statement (Box 263)
        - Draft A, pp. 1b-333, 4 folders (Box 263)
        - Draft A, pp. 334-433, some pages look like they are missing, but reads sequentially; 1 folder (Box 264)
        - Draft B "2/15/77", 3 folders (Box 264)
        - Draft C "2/15/77" pp. 1-250, 2 folders (Box 264)
        - Draft C "2/15/77" pp. 251-482, 2 folders (Box 265)
        - Draft D "2/15/77", 3 folders (Box 265)
        - Draft E "2/15/77" pp. 1-150, 1 folder (Box 265)
        - Draft E "2/15/77" pp. 151-433, 2 folders (Box 266)
        - Draft F "5/10/77", 3 folders (Box 266)
        - Draft G "5/10/77" pp. 1-152, 1 folder (Box 266)
        - Draft G "5/10/77" pp. 153-411, 2 folders (Box 267)
        - Draft H, 4 folders (Box 267)
        - Draft I pp. xi-100, 1 folder (Box 267)
        - Draft I pp. 101-441, 3 folders (Box 268)
      - Chapter drafts
        - Preface, Introduction (Box 268)
        - Preface to the Syracuse University Press Edition (Box 268)
        - Chapter 1 (The Myth of Psychotherapy: Metamorphizing Medical Treatment) (Box 268)
        - Chapter 2 (Persuading Persons: Rhetoric as Remedy) (Box 268)
        - Chapter 3 (Curing Souls: Religion as Remedy) (Box 268)
        - Chapter 4 (Franz Anton Mesmer: Metamorphizing Magnetism) (Box 268)
        - Chapter 5 (Johann Christian Heinroth: Repression as Remedy) (Box 268)
        - Chapter 7 (The Psychoanalytic Movement: Franchising the Freudian Faith) (Box 268)
        - Chapter 9 (Sigmund Freud: The Jewish Avenger) (Box 268)
        - Chapter 10 (Carl Gustav Jung: Pastor Without a Pulpit (Box 269)
        - Chapter 11 (Psychotherapy: Medicine, Religion, and Power) (Box 269)
        - Chapter 12 (Psychotherapy and Language: Contemporary Uses and Abuses) (Box 269)
      - Drafts, miscellaneous (Box 269)
      - Galleys
        - Galley A, "Final Galley" (Box 316)
        - Galley B, "Foundry Proof" (Box 317)
      - Marked-up proof, photocopy (Box 269)
      - Proof, photocopy, with corrections; 2 folders (Box 269)
      - Promotional materials (Box 269)
      - Reviews (Box 269)
    - Our Right to Drugs: The Case for a Free Market
      - Drafts, "Cracking the Constitution: Resisting the Twin Temptations of Using and Waging Wars on Drugs", earlier working title for book, as is "Dope" (with same subtitle)
        - Draft A, pp. 1-130, 1 folder (Box 269)
        - Draft A, pp. 131-261, 1 folder (Box 270)
        - Draft B, 2 folders (Box 270)
        - Draft C, incomplete (Box 270)
        - Draft D, incomplete (Box 270)
      - Chapter drafts, arranged alphabetically
        - Table of Contents (Box 270)
        - Preface (Box 270)
        - Introduction (Box 270)
        - Crack is Genocide (Box 270)
        - Drug Control Versus Pain Control (Box 270)
        - Drugs as Property: the Right We Rejected (Box 270)
        - The Economic Principle Applies to All Human Action, 2 folders (Box 270)
        - Just Say No (Box 271)
        - Reclaiming the Right to Drugs: the Task Ahead (Box 271)
        - Redeemer Nation, 2 folders (Box 271)
        - To Control, Legalize (Box 271)
        - Epilogue, also entitled "End" (Box 272)
      - Drafts, "The Right to Drugs: Our Fear and Rejection of a Free Pharmaceutical Market and Their Consequences", earlier working title for book
        - Draft A, 2 folders (Box 272)
        - Draft B, spiral-bound (Box 272)
        - Draft C, spiral-bound (Box 272)
        - Miscellaneous, synopsis and title suggestions (Box 273)
      - "Our Right to Drugs"